#### Contact

richardyd@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/richard-depestre-7b025b46 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

DAX

**Data Modeling** 

Microsoft Power BI

#### Certifications

Power BI Data Modeling with DAX

# Richard Depestre

Software Engineer at Corporate Information Management Services West Hartford

## Summary

Full Stack Data Analyst with a certificate in data transformation, data analysis, data presentation and visualization, and Machine Learning from Columbia University. Experienced Software Engineer. Worked in the Insurance and Healthcare industries on simplifying user interfaces, integrating heterogeneous applications, data, and reporting, fine-tuning desktop and server applications using a variety of Windows-based development tools. Possess excellent technical, problem-solving, and interpersonal skills.

# Experience

Corporate Information Management Services Software Engineer August 2019 - Present (2 years 2 months) Waterbury, Connecticut, United States

REST API Development | Unilever N. A

- Contracted to automate, document, and deploy the security management of Oracle Planning and Budgeting Cloud Service (PBCS) via API's managed by Xpandion workflow system.
- Project was part of an enterprise initiative to help streamline security management across the enterprise and lower total cost and time to manage this function.
- As software engineer, leveraged web service clients including MuleSoft,
   Postman and SOAP UI to test and document deficiencies in REST API.
   Presented findings to product Owners at Oracle.

Development and Maintenance | Datalynx 4/2012 - 4/2013 - 8/2019 - present

- Automating, with SQL Server scripts and REST APIs, the extraction of our clients' payroll data for further transformation, and analysis,
- Contracted to perform enhancements to client-facing, hosted CRM systems serving the Automotive Aftermarket industry.
- As Designer/Software Engineer created custom reports in SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS).

Utilized .NET C# to create SOAP web services and facilitate data exchanges between modules.

- Developed and supported internal SQL Server application for CRM and Reporting system for SaaS company.

Disability Management Services, Inc.
Software Engineer
July 2018 - August 2019 (1 year 2 months)
Springfield, Massachusetts Metropolitan Area

- Hired as Software Engineer to develop enhancements to proprietary financial software.
- Created a SQL and C# customized ETL process and improved by 45%
   the loading of transformed clients' data onto the company's proprietary data storage platform.
- Designed, coded, and implemented into QA and Production environments,
   VB.NET, VBA solutions to stamp application's defects per business
   requirements.

# Valassis Application Developer 2016 - July 2018 (2 years) Hartford, Connecticut Area

Hired to stabilize, support and extend a Sales Tax Calculation (STC) applications suite.

- Designed and coded enhancements to interfaces, business rules and data components;
- Coordinated with Release Management continuous and timely deployment of new releases and code fixes;
- Responded to daily incidents and assisted users with application and workflows incidents:
- Automated with SQL workflows for executing application data transformations and injections;
- Championed the creation of a One-Desktop solution and run STC on virtual Windows 2012 Remote Servers:
- \* Worked with Systems Engineering and stood up a virtual Load-Balancing-multiple-server architecture;
- \* Spearheaded the conversion of all application modules to utilize upgraded API Libraries;
- \* Planned and coordinated Performance/Load testing efforts;

\* Wrote deployment guidelines for application migration to new virtual environment.

Hands-on design and development with Visual Basic .Net, Net Framework 2.0, MS Office 2013, VBA, SQL Server, OLE Automation, 64-bit Windows OS.

#### Chubb

Senior Technical Consultant 2013 - 2016 (3 years)

Simsbury, Connecticut

Contracted to assist Development team with achieving Compliance Certification and roll-out of new products.

- Coded and integrated newly designed insurance forms into existing applications;
- Actively supported roll-out of new products;
- Designed and coded enhancements to application user interface components;
- Created and deployed SQL scripts to support data enhancements to application.

Utilized Visual Basic .Net, Net Framework 2.0, MS Office 2010, Informix database, OLE Automation, XML for all design and development activities.

## Knights of Columbus

Consultant

2013 - 2013 (less than a year)

New Haven, Connecticut

Contracted to assist with Application certification, Web Portal deployment, Enterprise Disaster Recovery (DR), and Annuity application replacement.

#### **Application Certification**

- Researched application documentation, interviewed SME and created, in Visio, state diagrams representing four major enterprise multi-tiered applications in their respective environments;
- \* Presented diagrams to applications owner and production support personnel.

#### Web Portal Deployment

- Authored run book for the application;
- Configured and deployed CA Erwin Web Portal
- \* Worked with Systems Administrator and offered Single-Sign-On feature to users via LDAP;

- Tested application thoroughly in a virtual Test environment then deployed it to Production.

#### AWD Workflow and Document imaging

- Created, in PowerShell, scripts that monitor files activity on FTP-file servers and notify support personnel.

#### **Enterprise Disaster Recovery**

- Created powershell scripts to:
- \* Automate Disaster Recovery tasks;
- \* Check status of array of servers;
- \* Inventory and tally servers' hardware and software before and after DR activities;
- \* Generate comparison results for management report and analysis.
- Compiled and implemented scripts on both 64 and 32-bit laptops.

#### **Annuity Application Replacement**

- Engaged Systems Administration and created a virtual shared storage for a batch process to retrieve files created by its predecessors and store outputs it generated;
- Conceived a Visio diagram that depicts the enterprise-wide process to help in business and technical discussions;
- Installed, configured the application and tested it in a virtual environment then created scripts and run-book to promote it in a production environment.
   Hands-on development with PowerGUI 3.7, PowerShell 2.0, Net Framework 2.0, MS Office 2007, MS Visio.

#### Cigna

Consultant

2011 - 2013 (2 years)

Hartford, Connecticut Area

Tools: Autonomy Interwoven TeamSite 7.2, HTML, XML, Agile, Rally. Contracted Test and Enhance On-line Experience Program.

- Analyzed specifications and created, deployed then tested Data Capture Records (DCR);
- Updated content of existing DCR, verified accuracy of content and deployed to specified servers;
- Created and updated test cases, in XML, to validate the accuracy of business requirements;
- Earnestly worked on defects screening and resolution.

UnitedHealth Group Application Developer 2007 - 2008 (1 year)

- Coded satellite components to a multi-tiers desktop application;
- Productively worked with teammates to quickly and effectively resolve defects identified during testing activities;
- Created in ASP. Net and C# a graphical user interface that facilitated the immediate delivery of customized policy data that meet our business partners request criteria;
- Analyzed business requirements for project to migrate the CareOne Coordination application to a WPF/WCF-based framework.
   Hands-on coding with C# 2.0, ASP.Net, Visual Basic 6.0, MS Visio.

Data Capture Solutions Senior Software Developer 2006 - 2007 (1 year) Ellington, Connecticut

Hired to design and develop an asset tracking application for capturing and storing on hand-held devices bar-coded data then marshalling them to a SQL Server database;

Thoroughly designed then coded and tested the application;

- Coordinated application deployment on several Symbol-manufactured rugged devices powered by Pocket-PC or Windows CE 5.0 operating system;
- Maintained and improved a multi-threading 'Load Balancing' console application that managed and processed data requests from hand-held devices;
- Actively participated and contributed valuable technical insights to enterpriselevel product architecture discussions.

Hands-on development with C# 2.0, SQL Server 2000, MS Visio, UML.

#### Cigna

Senior Designer/Developer 2003 - 2006 (3 years)

Hartford, Connecticut Area

Recruited for driving the integration and migration of several Claim Processing applications.

- Worked diligently to present Business Partners, Application Architecture Group with road-map for converting and integrating identified Claim systems;
- \* Authored then registered application infrastructure and security diagrams with Architecture Directorate.

- Conceived software development specifications for offshore and on-site development teams;
- Developed and maintained test scenarios and data.
- Spearheaded the development of message-driven components and facilitate the integration of mainframe services and desktop applications via IBM MQ;
- Thoroughly designed and coded several bridge-components;
- Coded and tested a batch process that validated Data Feeds from third-party vendors and other Lines of Business:
- \* Authored visual tools to help maintain batch process.
- Re-factored a PowerBuilder console application to yield 30% performance improvement.
- Constructively collaborated with IBM's development team to improve their Host On-Demand web-based software;
- Coordinated testing sessions for on-site and off-site users;
- Coordinated components Release and Implementation activities;
- Led team in researching and fixing technical and application defects.
- Used Gantt chart to monitor development tasks progress against project plan; provided weekly, at times daily statuses to project managers.

Hands-on coding and design in Visual Basic .Net, C#, MQ Series, Altova Enterprise 2006, UDB, MS Visio, UML.

# Education

Columbia University in the City of New York
Certificate, Data Analytics · (February 2021 - August 2021)

**Drexel University** 

Master of Science (MS), Management Information Systems · (2000)

Bentley College

Bachelor of Science (BS), Accounting and Computer Science · (1994)